HARRISON CHEGE K

PERSONAL DATA

Name: Harrison Chege Kamau

Date of Birth: 13th November 1991 | Nationality: Kenyan Address: P.O. BOX 8688-00200, Nairobi. Kenya.

Phone Number: +254 717725010 | Email address: kamauharrison87@gmail.com

Career Objective

To optimally use my coding skills and experience as a part of a challenging like-minded tech team in a result-oriented company and to overcome diverse challenges and attribute them positively to growth in a liberalized and highly competitive business environment.

HIGHLIGHTS & SKILLS

- JavaScript, Python, Flask, MEAN Stack, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Yeoman, GitHub and Linux
- Technology fascist
- Interpersonal skills
- Implement coherent strategies
- Results oriented
- Excellent communication skills
- Developing relationships
- SPSS, STATA, R

- Self-directed
- Analytical mind
- Quick learner
- Foosball Table pro

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Business analyst

Oct 2014 - Sep 2015

Hydro Universe Company Ltd. Duties performed;

- Testing systems and providing competitive commercial solutions.
- Task analysis and evaluating surveys and workshop results.
- Advising senior management.
- Use of IT skills to come up with IT solutions imperative for competitive ability.
- Training staff on how to use any newly deployed software or system
- Working with internal engineering teams to design, develop and implement internal solutions

Mercury Printers, Duties performed;

- Oversee every transaction related to purchase, sale and management of resources
- Computer packages instructor
- Liaise with the business owner in the expansion and growth strategies.
- Total oversight on all business activities

Contractual Property Manager

Jan 2014 - April 2014

Havilaplus Estate Consultant, Duties performed;

- Property management
- Staff recruitment and training
- Company's account management
- Rent collection and property maintenance
- Marketing and PR

Credit documentation officer/ Intern July 2013-Jan 2014

Faulu Kenya DTM Ltd. Key responsibilities;

- Receive disbursed loan application forms within Branch Credit Committee (BCC) limits and verify against the batch proofing schedule.
- Review the loan application forms for errors and omissions, compliance with the laid credit policies and Procedures and guidelines issued from time regarding administration of credit.
- Responsible for communication calling for additional or missing documents, perfection of securities / conditions within 12 hours from receipt of the batches.
- Confirm that the loans are maintained in the system properly, all charges collected and loan pay offs cleared.
- Organize proper prompt system of filing and retrieval of all loan forms with the archives section.
- Generate compliance reports for use in decision making and performance appraisals

St. Michael's Educational Center. Responsibilities;

- Taught Biology, Mathematics, Physics & Agriculture.
- Served as the Christian Union Patron
- Counseled students on career and real life approaches.
- Conjured with the school principal on students' outreach activities.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer

Oct 2015 - Dec 2015

The Dev School, Strathmore University, Nairobi

Bachelors' Degree in Economics & Statistics

May 2011- Dec 2014

The University of Nairobi

Kenya Certificate of secondary school

Feb 2006- Nov 2009

William Ng'iru High School

• Attained B-

Online courses

Introduction to Computer Science and Programming

MIT

Learning from Data

California University of Technology.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- Participated in IMF research and evaluation projects 2014 2015
- Participated in a Tax seminar at Times Tower where we were taught about Kenyan tax systems in entirety. **June 2013**
- Participated in the "Annual UNV Students' Symposium on Volunteerism" held at the University of Nairobi, main campus (awarded a certificate). Nov 2012
- Participated in the "Regional Economic Outlook-Sub- Saharan Africa" talk by IMF resident representative DR. Ragnar Gudmundsson held at the University of Nairobi, main campus (awarded a certificate) July 2011

MEMBERSHIP

- Member of Swahili Box Mombasa Tech Team
- Member of iHub Nairobi
- Member of Python Mombasa group
- Member of Economics Students' Association (ECOSA), University of Nairobi.
- Member of University Students Initiative to Society (USIS) Voluntary organization
- Member of In-depth Research Services (IRES)

LANGUAGES AND IT

English (Proficiency); Swahili (Proficiency);

Full Stack Developer

REFERENCE

Leon Kiptum

Head of Consumer Banking, Family Bank

P.O. Box 74145-00200, Nairobi.

Cell: +254722813225.

Email: lkiptum@familybank.co.ke

• Agnes Mungai

Senior Supervisor, Credit Department, Faulu Kenya DTM Ltd.

P.O. Box 60240-00200, Nairobi.

Cell: +254720408004.

Email: Agnes.mungai@faulukenya.com

• George MuiruKahuki

Property Manager, Havilaplus Estates.

P.O. Box 57-00625, Nairobi

Cell: +254727740191.

Email: jeorgemuiru@gmail.com